<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools on Little Columns</title>
    <link>http://www.littlecolumns.com/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools on Little Columns</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 09:05:37 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.littlecolumns.com/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Little Geocoder</title>
      <link>http://www.littlecolumns.com/tools/little-geocoder/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 09:05:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.littlecolumns.com/tools/little-geocoder/</guid>
      <description>Little Geocoder is a tiny tool that you can use to convert data from United States street addresses to geocoded latitude/longitude pairs. Gazillions of addresses, for free.
It was built on top of the Los Angeles Times&amp;rsquo; python-censusbatchgeocoder, that in turn uses the US Census Bureau&amp;rsquo;s Geocoding Service. They both were really helpful to geocode addresses in the US, but you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t need to know Python to get that kind of stuff to work!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pathwinder</title>
      <link>http://www.littlecolumns.com/tools/pathwinder/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 09:05:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.littlecolumns.com/tools/pathwinder/</guid>
      <description>Pathwinder allows you to view and edit your $PATH on OS X without going through the trouble of opening up your ~/.bash_profile, digging through config files, or even opening up Terminal.
Remove items from your $PATH by unchecking a box, or add new ones by clicking a button. It&amp;rsquo;s just that easy. Automatic backups, too, in case you make a mistake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Wrangler</title>
      <link>http://www.littlecolumns.com/tools/python-wrangler/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 09:05:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.littlecolumns.com/tools/python-wrangler/</guid>
      <description>Python Wrangler helps you install Python in a nice, pleasant, perfect way. Already installed it? Four times? Eighteen times? No problem, Python Wrangler can also help you understand, organize, and remove the Python installations hiding on your computer.
It&amp;rsquo;s highly opinionated, so you don&amp;rsquo;t need to think too hard: just do what Python Wrangler says and you&amp;rsquo;ll end up with a nice setup. Have opinions of your own? No worries, just use the data it gives you to clean up your system according to your own best practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Wrangler Notes</title>
      <link>http://www.littlecolumns.com/tools/python-wrangler-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 09:05:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.littlecolumns.com/tools/python-wrangler-notes/</guid>
      <description>Python Wrangler helps you install Python in a nice, pleasant, perfect way. But what do you do once you&amp;rsquo;re done? Read on!

Your default Python If you visit the command line and type python, it will run your &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; Python.

Installing packages (Windows) Your usual pip install should work fine, but since we&amp;rsquo;re not using Anaconda some of the more technical packages might be trouble for Windows users.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>